字幕来源：YYeTs字幕组
字幕协调&特效：101eagle
压制：101eagle
UP：101eagle
主演: 杰克・尼科尔森
飞  越  疯  人  院
路易斯・佛莱契
威廉・瑞菲德
编剧：劳伦斯・奥邦  博・古德曼
制片：索尔・萨兹  麦克・道格拉斯
导演：米洛斯・福尔曼
-早安  瑞秋小姐  -早安
-Good morning, Miss Ratched.  -Good morning.
-早安  瑞秋小姐  -华盛顿先生
-Good morning, Miss Ratched.  -Mr. Washington.
-早安  瑞秋小姐  -早安
-Good morning, Miss Ratched.  -Good morning.
-早安  巴西尼  -早安
-Good morning, Bancini.  -Good morning.
感觉怎么样?
How are you feeling?
还可以
Rested.
吃药时间到了
Medication time.
好了  下一位
Okay, move it up!
佛兰迪克森先生  小心点
Mr. Fredrickson, here.
果汁
Juice.
酋长
Chief.
好了朋友  来吧
Okay, my friend, let's go.
文件在这里  请你签名
Here's his papers, and I'm gonna need a signature.
嗨
Hi.
-麦克墨菲先生到了  -好的
-Mr. McMurphy's here.  -All right.
好了  说吧
All right, I'm ready.
一双袜子
Okay. One pair of socks.
一件T恤
T-shirt.
嗨
Hi.
天啊  你跟壮得跟山一般
Goddamn, boy, you're as big as a mountain.
像是踢美式足球的
Look like you might have played some football.
你叫什么?
What's your name?
他...听...不...懂你的话
He can't hear you. He's deaf.
他是个既聋...又笨的...印地安人
Deaf and dumb Indian.
是这样吗?
Is that so?
快点  毕比
Come on, Bibbit.
发不出声音吗
Can't even make a sound, huh?
如何?
How?
梅花大  梅花J
Club lead. Jack of clubs.
孩子  你叫什么名字?
What's your name, son?
比利・毕比
Billy Bibbit.
很高兴认识你  比利  我叫麦克墨菲
Glad to know you, Bill. McMurphy's mine.
还是老查理・契士威克厉害
That's old Charlie Cheswick's cards.
那是他的黑桃A
That's his ace of spades.
换你了  比利
Your turn, Bill.
-把它放在...  -等一下...
-Put one of them on it, will you?  -Wait a minute.
这次我可以赢  我赢了
Oh, I can win that one. I win.
你赢了这一盘?
Oh, you overtrumped?
当然
Sure.
小木偶比利  你没有黑桃吗?
Pinochle, Bill? For any spades?
赌注是多大
What's the bid?
5块...  5块5
Five... Five-fifty.
你喜欢看别人的牌  是吗?
You like to look at other people's cards, do you?
是的
Yes.
有看过这种牌吗?
Ever seen this one?
-拜托  马堤尼  -马堤尼!
-Come on, Martini.  -Martini!
马堤尼  你到底玩不玩呢?
Martini, will you? Will you play a club?
现在换谁了?
Whose turn is it now?
让我来看看  他赢了
Well, let's see, he trumped...
你要去哪里?
Where you going?
-你不玩了吗?  -他怎么了?
-Aren't you gonna play?  -What's the matter with him?
你不玩了吗  马堤尼?  到底...
Aren't you gonna play, Martini?
马堤尼  我要玩...
Martini? I wanna play.
比利  我想要...
Billy, I wanna win some...
控制一下好不好
Get a grip on yourself, will you?
请进
Yes?
医生  麦克墨菲先生来了
Mr. McMurphy's here, Doc.
非常好  请他进来吧
Good, have him come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
麦克墨菲  我是史贝菲医生
McMurphy, I'm Dr. Spivey.
史贝菲医生  很高兴认识你
Dr. Spivey, what a pleasure it is to meet you.
很好  拿张椅子坐下  我们谈谈
Sure. Pull up a chair, sit down and let's talk.
好的
Sure.
麦克墨菲
R.P. McMurphy.
那条鱼真大
That's a hell of a fish there, Doc.
-是不是很棒  -对
-Isn't that a dandy?  -Yeah.
大概有40磅吧?
It's about 40 pounds, ain't it?
-没有  32磅  -32磅...
-No, 32.  -Thirty-two...
告诉你吧
But I'll tell you,
照相时我用尽力气...
it took every bit of strength I had to hold it out there...
才能抓住它
while the guy took the picture.
是需要好大的力气
Every damn bit.
我想那铁链一点用也没有
Probably that chain didn't help it any, either.
你没有连铁链一起秤吧
You didn't weigh the chain, did you, Doc?
没有
No, I didn't weigh the chain.
我对这照片引以为傲
But I'll tell you, I'm awfully proud of that picture.
那是我第一次钓到那种鱼
That's the first Chinooker I ever caught.
好大的一条鱼
It's a nice one.
蓝道・派崔克・麦克墨菲
Randall Patrick McMurphy.
38岁
Thirty-eight years old.
告诉我...
What can you tell me about...
你为什么会被送到这里来?
Why you've been sent over here?
我不知道啊
I don't know.
上面没有写吗?
What's it say there?
-你介意我抽烟吗?  -不会  不介意
-Mind if I smoke?  -No, go right ahead.
上面写了几件事
Well, it says several things here.
有妄想症
Said you'd been belligerent.
没有许可就说话
Talked when unauthorized.
工作态度很差  懒惰
You've been resentful in attitude toward work, in general. That you're lazy.
在课堂上吃嚼香糖
Chewing gum in class.
真正原因是...
Well, the real reason that you've been sent over here...
他们希望你被测试
is because they wanted you to be evaluated.
确定你是否有精神病
To determine whether or not you're mentally ill.
这才是真正的原因
This is the real reason.
你觉得他们为什么要这样想呢?
Why do you think they might think that?
我想可能是我...
Well, as near as I can figure out, it's cause I...
常常打架闹事
fight and fuck too much.
在监狱里吗?
In the penitentiary?
不...你是说...
No, no, no, you mean why...
为什么要把你从劳动农场...
Why did you get sent over here...
送到这里来呢?
from the work farm?
我真的不知道  医生
Well, I really don't know, Doc.
这上面写着...
It says here that you went around...
-让我看看...  -是他们找我麻烦
-Let me just take a look...  -It ain't up to me, you know.
1...
One...
2  3...
two, three...
4...
four...
你至少有...
You've got at least...
5次因闹事被逮捕
five arrests for assault.
这又怎么说?
What can you tell me about that?
5次打架?
Five fights, huh?
洛基打了40次  结果变成百万富翁
Rocky Marciano's got 40, and he's a millionaire.
-确实  -确实
-That's true.  -That is true.
你还与...
Of course, it's true that you went in for...
未成年人发生性关系
statutory rape.
这次是真的吧?
That's true, is it not, this time?
完全正确  可是医生...
Absolutely true. But, Doc...
她虽然只有15岁  但看起来像35岁...
she was 15 years old going on 35, Doc...
她告诉我她已经成年了  而且她...
and she told me she was 18, and she was...
说她是自愿的
very willing, you know what I mean?
我无法抵挡那个诱惑
I practically had to take to sewing my pants shut.
但是只有你跟我知道...
But between you and me...
她或许只有15岁  但是看到那个性感的臀部...
she might have been 15. When you get that little red beaver...
就在你眼前  我想那不算疯狂
right up there in front of you, I don't think it's crazy at all.
你也会那样做
And I don't think you do, either.
我听到了
I hear what you're saying.
没有男人可以抵挡那种诱惑
No man alive could resist that. That's why I got into jail to begin with.
这就是我进监狱的原因...
And now they're telling me I'm crazy over here...
只因为我不安静坐在那边
Cause I don't sit there like a goddamn vegetable.
这根本就不是疯了
It don't make a bit of sense to me.
如果这就是疯狂的话...
If that's what being crazy is...
那我跟街上那些疯子...
Then I'm senseless, out of it, gone down the road, whacko...
的确没有什么两样
but, no more, no less. That's it.
老实说  麦克墨菲  文件上面写的...
To be honest with you, McMurphy what it says here...
是这样...
is that...
他们觉得...
they think...
这只是你逃避工作的藉口
you've been faking it in order to get out of your work detail.
你认为如何呢
What do you think about that?
你认为我是这样的人吗?
Do I look like that kind of guy to you?
让我们先不要下定论  好吧
Let's just be frank for a minute. All right, Randall, if you would.
告诉我...
Tell me...
你觉得你的精神有问题吗?
Do you think there's anything wrong with your mind, really?
不可能的  医生
Not a thing, Doc.
我可是现代科技产物
I'm a goddamn marvel of modern science.
你会在这边待一段时间  好让我们可以测试你
You're gonna be here for a period for us to evaluate you.
我们需要来诊断你
We're gonna study you.
然后我们会下结论  看看该怎么做...
We'll make our determinations as to what we're going to do...
该给你哪些必须的治疗
and give you the necessary treatment as indicated.
让我告诉你  医生
Doc, let me just tell you this.
我会百分之百的合作
I'm here to cooperate with you 100 percent.
百分之百
A hundred percent.
我会非常的合作  请你拭目以待
I'll be just right down the line with you. You watch.
因为我想我们会发现...
Cause I think we ought to get to the bottom of...
真正的麦克墨菲
R.P.McMurphy.
伸展手臂
The scythe.
我好累
I'm awfully tired.
坐下
Sit down.
我很累
I'm tired.
好点了吗?
Is that better?
艾斯渥斯先生...
Mr. Ellsworth...
你在整自己
you'll wear yourself out.
好了  各位  让我们开始
All right, gentlemen, let's begin.
在星期五的会议中...
At the close of Friday's meeting...
我们论论到哈定先生和他太太的问题
we were discussing Mr. Harding's problem concerning his wife.
哈定先生说他的太太让他觉得不舒服...
Mr. Harding stated that his wife made him uneasy...
因为常常她注视着街上的男人
because she drew stares from men on the street.
对吧  哈定先生?
Is that correct, Mr. Harding?
是的
Yes.
没错
That's correct.
他同时也想给她藉口...
He also thinks he may have given her reason...
去外面寻找性生活  但是他说不出口
to seek sexual attention elsewhere, but he wasn't able to say how.
哈定先生对他太太说过
Mr. Harding has been heard to say to his wife:
我恨你
"I hate you."
我不想再见到你
"I don't ever want to see you again."
你背叛我
"You've betrayed me."
有人要发表意见吗?
So, does anyone care to touch on this further?
史肯隆先生  你要起个头吗?
Mr. Scanlon, would you begin today?
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
比利  你呢?
Billy, how about you?
不了  女士
No, no, ma'am.
我希望有一次会议是由你开始发言的
I'd like to write in my book that you began the meeting.
只要一次
Just once.
马堤尼先生?
Mr. Martini?
你有在听吗?
Are you with us?
是的
Yes.
你要开始讲吗?
Would you like to begin?
契士威克先生呢?
Mr. Cheswick?
-我吗?  -是的
-Me?  -Yes.
这里没有一个人对此有意见吗?
You mean there's not a man here who has an opinion on this matter?
好吧
All right.
哈定先生...
Mr. Harding...
你曾说过你不只一次怀疑...
you've stated on more than one occasion...
你太太在外面偷人
that you suspected your wife of seeing other men.
是的!
Oh, yes!
我非常怀疑她
Yes, very much, I suspect her.
我真的怀疑她
I suspect her.
或许你可以告诉我们  你为何...
Maybe you can tell us why...
怀疑她
you suspect her.
我只能说...
Well, I can only...
那只是推论
speculate as to the reasons why.
你有没有这样推论过  哈定先生...
Have you ever speculated, Mr. Harding...
或许你...
that perhaps you are...
对她失去了耐心...
impatient with your wife...
是因为她没办法达到你的心理要求?
because she doesn't meet your mental requirements?
或许是  但我唯一能够...
Perhaps. But you see, the only thing I can really...
推论的是  瑞秋护士...
speculate on, Nurse Ratched...
不管我老婆...
is the very existence of my life...
是否与我一起生活...
with or without my wife...
在人类的关系中...
in terms of the human relationships, the juxtaposition of...
人与人之间外表与内涵的并容
one person to another, the form, the content.
哈定  不要多说废话  直接讲重点
Harding, why don't you knock off the bullshit and get to the point?
这就是重点
This is the point.
塔波  这不是废话
This is the point, Taber. It's not bullshit.
我不只是在谈我的太太  我是在谈我的生活!
I'm not just talking about my wife, I'm talking about my life!
我不觉得你了解
I can't seem to get that through to you.
我不是在谈一个人
I'm not just talking about one person,
我在谈的跟每个人都有关!
I'm talking about everybody!
我是在谈外表!  我是在谈内涵!
I'm talking about form! I'm talking about content!
我是在谈人际关系!
I'm talking about interrelationships!
我是在谈神  恶魔  地狱  天堂!
I'm talking about God, the Devil, Hell, Heaven!
你懂了吗?
Do you understand? Finally?
哈定  我不敢相信  你真是他妈笨得可以
Yeah, Harding, you're so fucking dumb I can't believe it.
我觉得很奇怪  非常奇怪
It makes me feel very peculiar, very peculiar...
-你说话就像是那个  -什么?
-when you throw in something like that.  -Why?
有什么"奇怪"的  哈定?
What does that mean, "peculiar," Harding?
-奇怪?  -奇怪?
-Peculiar?  -Peculiar?
我告诉过你们
I'm gonna tell you guys something.
你们就是不想学
You just don't want to learn anything.
你们就是不想听别人说话
You just don't want to listen to anybody.
他是有智慧的!
He's got intelligence!
你从来没有听过"奇怪"这个字眼吗?
You've never heard the word "peculiar"?
你到底要说什么?
Say, what are you trying to say?
你说我疯了吗?  是不是?
You trying to say I'm queer? Is that it?
小马利・安?  小玛茱莉・珍?
Little Mary Ann? Little Marjorie Jane?
是这样吗?  你是不是想告诉我这些?
Is that it? Is that what you're trying to tell me?
这就是你所谓的沟通吗?
Is that your idea of communicating something to me? Is it?
是这样吗?
Well, is it?
他们的话题都围绕着你  哈定
They're all crowding in on you, Mr. Harding.
他们的都围着你
They're all ganging up on you.
这是新闻吗?
Is that news?
不...有的时候他们也围攻我  但是我...
They sometimes want to gang up on me, too, but I...
契士威克  帮个忙
Cheswick, do me a favor.
放轻松点
Take it easy.
-不要帮倒忙  -但是我只是...
-And stay off my side.  -But I only wanna...
我只是要帮你
I only wanna help you.
-我懂  -但是你不要我...?
-I understand.  -But don't you want me to...?
-拜托!  -但是我只是要...
-Please!  -But I only want to...
-拜托!  -但是我只是想帮你
-Please!  -But I only want to help you.
拜托!
Please!
你看...
You see...
有一天  你间接暗示  你们两个...
the other day you made some allusions, both of you....
-性幻想?  -是的  是间接
-Illusions?  -Yes, allusions.
不是幻想  间接暗示...
Not illusions. Allusions...
我和我太太之间的性问题
to sexual problems I might be having with my wife.
就算是真的!  就算我知道是真的
All right, let's say it's true! Let's say I know it to be true.
但是你不知道!
But you don't!
如果你是用这种方法告诉我的话
If that's your idea of trying to tell me something,
你或许应该...
you have another...
你知道吗哈定
You know, Harding,
我想你是个下贱的混蛋!
I think you're some kind of morbid asshole or something!
-奇怪!  -混蛋
-Peculiar!  -Asshole again.
让你觉得很奇怪的事
It makes you feel peculiar.
我记得你一直在谈你的太太!
You've been talking about your wife ever since I can remember!
她一直存在你的心里...
You know, she's on your mind, and blah, blah, blah...
我不是在谈我的太太!
I'm not talking about my wife!
什么时候你的猪脑才会想通?
When are you gonna get that through your thick fucking head?
你什么时候可以把她放掉?
When are you gonna wise up and turn her loose?
-拜托!  -我不要听!
-Please!  -I don't want to hear it!
-我很累  -我不要听!
-I'm tired.  -I don't want to hear it!
我很累...
I'm tired...
我不要听...
I don't want to hear it...
全都是胡说...我很累...
It's a lot of baloney and I'm tired.
我不想听!
I don't want to hear it!
我知道你累了  我们都累了
We know you're tired. We're all tired.
我累是因为这全都是胡说八道
I'm tired and it's a lot of baloney.
巴西尼  你不累
You're not tired, Bancini.
不要碰我  滚开!
Take your hands off me!
自由时间  先生们
Recreation time, gentlemen.
巴士到了
The bus is waiting.
非隔离病患请上巴士
All nonrestricted patients please report to the bus.
玩过这个吗  酋长?
Ever play this game, Chief?
来吧  我来示范
Come on, I'll show you.
这是个老印地安游戏
Old Indian game.
这叫做..."把球放进洞"
It's called "put the ball in the hole."
现在  停在这边
Now, that ought to be just...Hold it right there.
好的
All right.
站在这里不动
Now, that's your spot. Don't move.
绝对不要动  你要站在这里  懂吗?
Never move. That's your spot, you understand?
不要移动  好了...
Right there. You don't move. Now...
拿着球
take the ball.
给  拿着
Here, take the ball.
就是这样抓紧它
That's it. Hold on to it.
不要太紧  酋长  不然你会把气都挤出来
Not too hard, Chief. You'll crush all the air out of it.
现在把它放进篮子里  懂吗?
We're gonna put her in the basket. You understand?
好的  现在举起你的手
All right. Now, raise up your arms.
把球举到空中  举起来
Raise the ball up in the air, Chief. Raise it up.
麦克墨菲?
McMurphy?
你跟他讲什么呢?  他什么都听不到
What the hell are you talking to him for? He can't hear a fucking thing.
我不是在跟他讲话  我只是在自言自语
I ain't talking to him. I'm talking to myself.
这样可以帮助我思考
It helps me think.
那也不能帮助他
Yeah, well, it don't help him none.
这也没差吧  不是吗?
Well, it don't hurt him, either, does it?
酋长  没差吧?
Don't hurt you, does it, Chief?
看吧  没差吧
See? Don't hurt him.
现在  酋长...
All right, now, Chief...
把手举到空中
Let's raise our hands up in the air.
举起来
Just raise them up.
懂吗?
Up, you understand?
举起来
Raise the hands up, here.
把手举起来
Up. Raise your hands up.
就是这样!  举直
Up! That's it! That's it! Up, all the way up.
举起来  真乖
All the way up. That's a baby, all right.
好了  现在...
Okay, now...
跳起来放进篮框里  酋长
Now, jump up in the air, and put it in the basket, Chief.
跳起来然后灌篮!
Jump up and dunk it in!
跳起来把球灌下去  酋长
Jump up in the air and stuff that son of a bitch in there, Chief.
休息一下  酋长
Take a rest, Chief.
待在这休息一下  我马上回来
Just stay right there. Take a rest. I'll be right back.
巴西尼  来一下
Bancini, come here for a minute.
你看起来很不错  过来这边一下
You're looking all right. Get right over here for a second.
站在这边
Now, just stand right there.
蹲下来一点点  站起来
Just get down a little bit. All right. Stand up.
站起来
Stand up. Go ahead.
很乖!  太好了
That's a baby! All right, you got her.
不错  现在去那边
All right. Now, over there.
传给我  酋长!  我空手切入!
Hit me, Chief! I got the moves! I got them, Chief!
停下来  把球给我
Hold it right there. Give me the ball.
把球给我  就是这样  谢谢  酋长
Give me the ball. That's it. Thank you, Chief.
现在...
Now...
停着不要动
hold it right there.
拿着球跳起来  放进篮框里
You take the ball, you jump up, and put it in the basket.
懂我的意思吗  放进去...巴西尼不要动
See what I mean? Put it... Bancini, hold still.
酋长看这里  拿着球
All right, Chief, here. Take the ball.
跳起来把它放进篮框里!
Now, jump up and put her in the basket, Chief!
Jump up and put her in the basket!
不是你  巴西尼
Not you, Bancini.
站直!  巴西尼你去哪里?
Raise up! Bancini, where you going?
我很累!
I'm tired!
快攻!  防守!  回去!
Fast break! Defense! Get back!
拜托  巴西尼  你要去哪里?
Come on, Bancini, where the fuck you going at?
将军  让这个人转过去
General, get this man around here.
就是这样  回去!
That's it, back!
回到酋长那边去
Over to Chief.
快攻!  快攻!  传给我  酋长!
Fast break! Fast break! Hit me, Chief!
传给我!
Hit me, baby!
放进篮框里  酋长!
Put it in the basket, Chief!
放进篮框里!
Put it in the basket!
好了
All right.
下注吧
Make the bets.
这是什么?
What's this?
下注
Make the bets.
这是十分钱  马堤尼
It's a dime, Martini.
我下五分钱
I bet a nickel.
最少要十分钱  马堤尼
A dime's the limit, Martini.
我下十分钱
I bet a dime.
这不是十分钱  马堤尼
This is not a dime, Martini.
这才是十分钱
This is a dime.
如果你分两半
If you break it in half...
你不会有两个五分钱  只是废物一堆
you don't get two nickels, you get shit.
拿去抽吧  懂吗?
Try and smoke it. You understand?
是的  你不懂!  开始了
You don't understand! All right, here they come.
契士拿到Q...
Queen to the Chesser, big bull to Tabulations...
比利拿到10  庄家拿到3
ten to Billy to match his whang, and the dealer gets a three.
再来一张  再来一张
Hit me. Hit me.
我不能给你  因为还没轮到你  懂了吗?
I can't hit you because it ain't your turn yet. You understand?
你看到这些人吗?  都是活人
You see these other people? These are the real ones.
都还没轮到他们
These are real people here.
契士  你要不要牌?
What'll you do, Ches? Hit or sit?
再一张
Hit me.
那是23点  契士威克
That's 23 up, Cheswick.
塔波你暴了  给我这个
Taber, you're busted. Give me this.
23...
Twenty-three.
-给我一张  -闭嘴!
-Hit me.  -Shut up!
塔波
Taber.
-给我十分钱!  -我是下一个  塔波
-Give me a dime!  -I'm next. Taber.
还没轮到你!
You're not next!
给我一张牌
Hit me.
-A  -再给我一张
-Ace.  -Hit me.
那是4还是14
That's 4 or 14.
不要了  比利呢?
Don't want any more. Billy?
-给我一张  -5
-Hit me. Hit me.  -Five.
你没有下注  马堤尼  我不能给你
You didn't make a bet, Martini. I can't hit you. Jesus Christ.
我下十分钱
I bet a dime.
好吧  开始
All right, here.
-牌面20  -不
-That's 20 showing.  -No.
-你的钱没了  -不
-Take your money.  -No.
这不是
It's not.
这是10  11  12  13
It's 10, 11, 12, 13.
你拿到一张Q  懂吗?
This is a fucking queen here, you understand?
你不能这样算
You don't count the this and the this.
再来一张
Hit me.
你牌面是20!
You got 20 showing!
再来一张  我要再一张牌
Hit me again. I want another card.
史肯隆  谁投第一局?
Scanlon, who's pitching the opener?
吃药时间到了
Medication time.
这不是Q!
This isn't a queen!
再一张牌
Mac, hit me.
-谁投第一局?  -再一张牌
-Who's pitching the opener?  -Hit me.
该死!
Jesus Christ Almighty!
你要玩牌还是要发疯?
Do you nuts wanna play cards or you wanna fucking jerk off?
要玩!
Play the game!
我甚至不能听到自己说话
I can't even hear myself think already, here.
到后面排队!
Stay back!
-对不起  我只是要找...  -到后面排队!
-Excuse me, ma'am. I just wanted to...  -Stay back!
病人不可以到护士站来
Patients aren't allowed in the nurses' station.
我只是想要...
Well, I just wanted to turn...
我们可以在外面讨论你的问题
When you're outside, we'll discuss whatever problem you have, okay?
病人不可以来护士站  好吗?
The patients are not allowed in the nurses' station. All right?
比利这是你的  让我插一下好吗?  谢谢
Let me get in here, will you, Hard-on? Thank you.
对不起女士
Excuse me, miss.
可不可以把声音关小一点...
Do you think it might be possible to turn that music down...
我们才可以听到彼此交谈
so maybe a couple of the boys could talk?
音乐是放给大家听的  麦克墨菲先生
That music is for everyone, Mr. McMurphy.
我知道  但是你能不能把它关小一点...
Yeah, I know, but do you think we might ease it down a little bit...
这样我们就不需要吼叫了
so maybe the boys didn't have to shout?
你大概不清楚...
What you probably don't realize...
这里有很多老人...
is that we have a lot of old men on this ward...
如果声音太小他们就听不到
who couldn't hear the music if we turned it lower.
音乐是他们仅有的
That music is all they have.
你的手把窗户弄脏了
Your hand is staining my window.
-对不起  女士  -没关系
-I'm sorry, ma'am.  -All right.
麦克墨菲先生  这是你的药
Mr. McMurphy, your medication.
这到底是什么?
What's in the horse pill?
只是药  对你好的药
It's just medicine. It's good for you.
但是我不喜欢吃
Yeah, but I don't like the idea of taking something
我不知道的东西
if I don't know what it is.
不要生气  麦克墨菲先生
Don't get upset, Mr. McMurphy.
我没有生气  毕波小姐
I'm not getting upset, Miss Pilbow.
我只是不喜欢有人喂我吃安眠药
It's just that I don't want anyone to try and slip me saltpeter.
你懂吗?
You know what I mean?
没关系  毕波护士
It's all right, Nurse Pilbow.
如果麦克墨菲先生不想用口服的话...
If Mr. McMurphy doesn't want to take his medication orally...
我想我们可以用别的方法
I'm sure we can arrange that he can have it some other way.
但是我想你不会喜欢的  麦克墨菲先生
But I don't think you'd like it, Mr. McMurphy.
你喜欢  对吧  哈定?
You'd like it, wouldn't you, Hard-on?
给我
Give it to me.
非常好
Good.
非常好!
Very good!
真好吃!
Yummy!
哈定先生?
Mr. Harding?
祝福我
Merci.
告诉我  情圣...
Tell me, Lover-boy...
为什么你不骂她呢?
why didn't you tell her to go fuck herself?
我的天啊
Jesus Christ.
很有趣是吧?
Funny, huh? That's funny, huh?
那可不太明智  她可能会看到
you know that wasn't very smart. She could have seen that.
上帝啊  她应付你们就够了
God Almighty, she's got you guys coming and going.
你以为她是万能的吗?
What do you think she is? Some kind of a champ or something?
不  我以为你是万能的
No, I thought you were the champ.
要打赌吗?
You want to bet?
赌什么?
Bet on what?
一个礼拜
One week.
我赌一个礼拜之内  我可以让她发疯...
I bet in one week I can put a bug so far up her ass...
甚至不知道什么时候上厕所  还是手表坏了
she won't know whether to shit or wind her wrist watch.
要打赌吗?  你要赌吗?
What do you say to that? Wanna bet? Do you wanna bet?
我只需要一个礼拜  谁要赌?
One week. That's all I need. Who wants to bet?
你要吗?  一块钱
You wanna bet? Bet a buck. One buck.
我要赌
I'll bet.
好  塔波  一块钱
Tabes in, one buck. Solid.
上一次我们曾讨论过...
Last time we were discussing...
哈定先生和他太太的问题...
Mr. Harding and the problem with his wife...
我想大家都有进步
and I think we were making a lot of progress.
今天谁要开始?
So who would like to begin today?
麦克墨菲先生?
Mr. McMurphy?
我在想你所说的...
I've been thinking about what you said about...
关于一吐心中的郁闷
you know, getting things off your chest.
有一些事我不吐不快
Well, there's a couple of things that I'd like to get off my chest.
非常好  麦克墨菲先生  请说
Well, that's very good, Mr. McMurphy. Go ahead.
或许你不知道...
Today, as you may or may not know, it doesn't matter...
今天是世界大赛的开幕赛
is the opening of the World Series.
我希望我们能够把工作时间调整到晚上...
What I'd like to suggest is that we change the work detail tonight...
这样我们可以看比赛
so that we can watch the ball game.
麦克墨菲先生  你所要求的...
Well, Mr. McMurphy, what you're asking...
是要我们改变一个非常好的时间表
is that we change a very carefully worked out schedule.
改变一点不会死吧?
A little change never hurt, huh?
一点?
A little variety?
这不是很正确  麦克墨菲先生
Well, it's not necessarily true, Mr. McMurphy.
你知道这里有些人
Some men on the ward
花了很长时间去适应这个时间表
take a long, long time to get used to the schedule.
如果现在改变  会对他们有所干扰
Change it now, and they might find it very disturbing.
去他妈的时间表!
Fuck the schedule!
在大赛之后可以改回来
They can go back to the schedule after the Series.
讨论的是现在的世界大赛  瑞秋护士
I'm talking about the World Series, Nurse Ratched.
现在没有办法
Well, anyway, this is no way to proceed about this.
我们来投票如何...
How would it be if we had a vote...
让多数决定吧?
and let majority rule?
太好了  现在来投吧
Great. Let's vote on her.
希望改的请举手
So, all those in favor raise your hands.
大家拜托
Okay, guys, come on.
举手一下
Put your hands up.
你们到底怎么了?  不想看世界大赛了吗?
What's the matter with you? Don't you want to watch the World Series?
拜托  举手一下...
Come on, get your hands up. It can do you some good...
多做点运动举起手来吧
to get some exercise, putting your arms up in the air.
非常好  拜托  让我们...
That's it. Come on, let's...
这是什么世界?
What is this crap?
我从来没有...我从来没有错过世界大赛
I watch the Series. I haven't missed the Series in years.
甚至是冷天
Even in the cooler.
有一次他们在冷天比赛还发生暴动
When I'm in the cooler they run it there or they'll have a riot.
你们到底怎么回事?  拜托  像个美国人吧!
What's the matter with you guys? Come on, be good Americans!
麦克墨菲先生  我只点到三票  而...
Well, Mr. McMurphy, I only count three votes, and...
那并不足以改变医院规则
that's not enough to change the ward policy.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
-换我  -来吧
-My turn.  -Okay, hot dice.
我要10...
I want a ten to go...
因为我需要钱
Cause I need cash.
我要去中央大道
I wanna get to Mediterranean Avenue.
10!  太好了
Big ten! Perfect.
两个5
Two fives.
-你在干嘛?  -旅馆
-What are you doing?  -Hotel.
-你在那边没有旅馆  -旅馆
-You do not have a hotel there.  -Hotel.
已经第三次了...
For the third time...
-你没有旅馆  -旅馆
you do not have a hotel on Boardwalk.  -Hotel.
-要花一千块钱和四栋绿色房子...  -旅馆
-It costs $1,000 and four green houses...  -Hotel.
-在百老汇街上盖一栋旅馆  -旅馆
-to put a hotel on Boardwalk.  -Hotel.
好好玩游戏  不要说废话
Play the game and knock off the bullshit.
玩游戏  哈定
Play the game, Harding.
你在讲什么?  我是在玩啊
What are you talking about? I am playing the game.
好好玩游戏!
Play the game!
不要烦我  我没有打扰你!
I ain't doing anything to you!
-什么叫废话?  -你的废话!
-What bullshit?  -Your bullshit!
-那你的废话?  -拜托  玩游戏!
-What about your bullshit?  -Come on, play the game!
-听着  不要碰我!  -玩游戏
-Listen, you keep your hands off me!  -Play the game.
我已经受够你了  听到了吗?
I've had enough bullshit out of you. You hear me?
-玩游戏  -为什么你要找我麻烦?
-Play the game.  -What the fuck are you picking on me for?
玩游戏  哈定
Play the game, Harding.
-我已经试着不理你  -玩游戏
-Look, I'm trying to ignore you, see?  -Just play the game.
不要碰我  你这狗娘养的!
Keep your hands off me, you son of a bitch!
不要碰我!  听到了吗?
Keep your hands off me! You hear me?
-来啊  -我已经受够了!
-Come on, come on.  -I can be pushed just so far, see!
玩游戏
Play the game.
你再碰我...再碰我一次的话
You touch me once more. Just touch me once more.
再一次?  再一次
Just once more, huh? Just once more.
-再碰我一次的话  -玩游戏  哈定!
-Just touch me once more.  -Play the game, Harding!
再碰我一次!
Just touch me once more!
天杀的!
Holy Jesus!
这就是你所谓的时间表?
Is that what your schedule does for you, Hard-on?
你这个该死的疯子!
Damn lunatic!
我不懂你在说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
那就这样一直湿吧  哈定
No? Well, then stay all wet, Harding, huh?
因为我要去市中心看世界大赛
Cause I'm going downtown and watch the World Series, anyway.
有人要跟我来吗?
Anybody want to come with me?
我要  我要跟你去!
I do, Mac. I wanna go with you!
契士  很好  还有其他人吗?
Ches, all right. Anybody else?
-去哪里?  -任何一家市中心的酒吧
-Where?  -Any bar downtown.
麦克  你没法...
Mac, you can't...
离开这里
can't get out of here.
要打赌吗?
Anybody want to bet?
胆小鬼!
Chicken shits!
或许只要他脱裤子给瑞秋护士看...
Maybe he'll just show Nurse Ratched his big thing...
她就会帮他开门
and she'll open the door for him.
或许我会...
Yeah, maybe I will...
或许我就用你的头
and then maybe I'll just use your thick skull
在墙上开一个大洞
and knock a hole in the wall.
菲尔  听到没?
Sefelt, see?
我的头就会像茄子一样爆开
Why? My head would squash like an eggplant.
不要管菲尔的头  我才不需要菲尔的头!
Fuck Sefelt's head, I don't need Sefelt's head!
我只要拿这个该死的东西
I'm gonna take this fucking thing,
把它丢出窗外...
I'll put it through the window...
然后我和契士威克会穿过走廊...
and me and my buddy Cheswick are gonna go out through the hall...
到市中心的一个酒吧  坐下后  边吹口哨...
downtown, sit down in a bar, wet our whistles...
边看比赛
and watch the ball game.
这就是赌注  有没有人要参加呢?
And that's the bet. Now, does anybody want any of it?
你要举起那个东西吗?
You're gonna lift that thing?
是的!  没错
Yeah! That's right.
我赌一块钱
I'll bet a buck.
塔波  一块钱
Taber, $1.
我赌十分钱
I bet a dime.
麦克  你不能...
Mac, you can't...
举起那个东西
can't lift that thing.
还有人要赌吗  哈定?
Anybody else want any of it? Hard-on?
我赌二十五块!
I'll bet $25!
二十五块钱  哈定!
$25, Hard-on!
麦克  没有人能举得起那个东西
Mac, nobody could ever lift that thing.
走开  你在吸我的氧气
Get out of my way, son. You're using my oxygen.
懂吗?
You know what I mean?
放弃了吗?
Giving up?
没有!  只是在热身
No! Just warming up.
热身
Warming up.
这次是真的
This will be the one.
来吧  宝贝
All right, baby.
我试过了  对吧?  该死!
But I tried, didn't I? Goddammit!
至少我试过了
At least I did that.
在投手丘上是左投手艾尔邓宁
And on the mound, the left-hander, Al Downing.
在我们下面有两个投手在热身
The two pitchers still warming up, right down below us.
1963年世界大赛第二场...
The second game of the 1963 World Series...
正在从洋基体育馆向您转播
is being brought to you from Yankee Stadium.
你有没有告诉那女孩你的感觉?
Did you tell the girl how you felt about her?
我去她的家...
I went over to her house...
在礼拜天下午...
one Sunday afternoon and...
我买了一些花...
and I brought her some flowers...
然后我说...
and I said...
西莉亚  你能...
Celia, will you...
嫁给我吗?
marry me?
比利
Billy.
为什么你要跟她结婚呢?
Why did you want to marry her?
我爱上了她
Well, I was in love with her.
你妈妈说你从来没有提过
Your mother told me that you never told her about it.
比利
Billy.
为什么你没有跟她说?
Why didn't you tell her about it?
比利
Billy.
那就是你第一次自杀吗?
Wasn't that the first time you tried to commit suicide?
我的天!
Oh, my God!
有问题吗  契士威克先生?
Yes, Mr. Cheswick?
瑞秋小姐...
Miss Ratched...
我想问你一个问题
I'd like to ask you a question, please.
请说
Go ahead.
如果...
You know, if...
比利不想提起...
Billy doesn't feel like talking...
我是说...你为什么要逼他?
I mean, why are you pressing him?
为什么我们不能谈点新的话题?
Why can't we go on to some new business?
契士威克先生  这个会谈的目的...
The business of this meeting, Mr. Cheswick...
就是治疗
is therapy.
我不懂这个  瑞秋小姐...
You know, I don't understand this, Miss Ratched...
因为我不...
because I don't...
麦克墨菲...
Mr. McMurphy...
昨天提到世界大赛
He said something yesterday about a World Series.
是棒球比赛?
A baseball game?
我从来没有去看过棒球比赛...
You know, and I've never been to a baseball game and...
我很想去看
I think I'd like to see one.
那会是一个很好的治疗对不对  瑞秋小姐?
That would be good therapy, too, wouldn't it, Miss Ratched?
我想昨天我们已经提过了
I thought we'd decided that issue.
我不是这样想的  我的意思是...
I don't think so, because, I mean...
昨天是讨论过...
we discussed that yesterday...
但是今天又有新的比赛  对不对  麦克?
and we have a new game today, I think, don't we, Mac?
对  契士  我们要重新投票  对吧?
That's right, Ches, and we want a new vote on it, don't we?
麦克墨菲先生  再投一次票  你就满足了吗?
Would one more vote satisfy you, Mr. McMurphy?
是的
Yeah.
我会满足
It'll satisfy me.
这是新一轮的投票
There's a vote before the group.
想要更改时间表的举手
Everyone in favor of changing the schedule, please raise your hand.
我要看到你们举手!
Okay, I want to see the hands. Come on!
你们这些疯子到底有没有种?
Which one of you nuts has got any guts?
太好了  就是这样!
All right. That's it!
我只数到了九张票  墨菲先生
I only count nine votes, Mr. McMurphy.
她只数到九张  只有九张票!  真棒
She only counts nine. Only nine! It's a landslide.
医院里面有十八个病人  麦克墨菲先生...
There are 18 patients on this ward, Mr. McMurphy...
必须过半数才能改变医院规定
and you have to have a majority to change ward policy.
你们可以把手放下来了
So you gentlemen can put your hands down.
你是说连这些狗娘养的都要算进去?
Are you trying to tell me that you're gonna count these?
他们甚至不知道我们在讲什么
These poor sons of bitches, they don't know what we're talking about.
我不同意  麦克墨菲先生
Well, I have to disagree with you, Mr. McMurphy.
这些人跟你一样都是医院一员
These men are members of the ward, just as you are.
好吧  我只需要一票  对吧?
All right. All I need is one vote, right?
对吧?
Right?
对
All right.
要看世界大赛吗?
Want to watch the World Series?
拜托  兄弟  这可是你的重要时刻
Come on in, pal. This could be a big moment for you.
你想看棒球大赛吗?
You wanna watch a baseball game?
你要看棒球?
You wanna watch baseball?
举手就好了  只要举手就可以了
Just raise that hand up. Just raise the hand up.
-怎么样  -我全都给她了
-What do you say? I gave it all to her.
抱歉
Sorry.
巴西尼  老马
Bancini, old horse.
你觉得怎样?  你要看棒球转播吗?
What do you say? You wanna watch the ball game on TV?
要看球赛吗  棒球  世界大赛
Wanna watch the ball game? Baseball? World Series?
你说怎样?  你累了吗?
What do you say, pal? You're tired?
只要举手  巴西尼  看球赛
Just raise your hand up, Bancini. Watch the ball game, huh?
我很累  非常累
I'm tired. Awfully tired.
好吧
Okay. All right.
你呢  伙计?
What about you, pal?
我们只需要一票  就一票
All we need's one vote. Just one vote.
就需要你这一票
Just your one vote. That's all we need.
只要举你的手  你的兄弟就可以看棒球比赛
Just raise your hand up and your buddies can watch the baseball game.
将军  你记得对吧?
General, you remember, don't you?
十月"星条旗歌"
October, the banner, the stars...
你能够...
"Oh, say can you..."
世界大赛  举起你的手  看见早晨的阳光...
The World Series. Raise your hand up, Gen.
只要举你的手
Just raise your hand up.
你呢  老兄  要看球赛吗?
What about you pal, huh? Wanna watch the ball game?
要看球赛吗?  只要一票  只要举你的...
Wanna watch the ball game, huh? Just one vote. Just raise your...
各位  散会了
Gentlemen, the meeting is adjourned.
看在老天的份上  你们这些该死的疯子...
For Christ's sake, isn't there one of you fucking maniacs...
知道我在说什么吗?
that knows what I'm talking about?
麦克墨菲先生?
Mr. McMurphy?
散会了
The meeting is adjourned.
等一下  等一分钟可以吗?
All right, just wait a minute, will you? Just one minute?
你可以明天再重新提出
You can bring the subject up again tomorrow.
酋长...
All right, Chief...
你是我们唯一的机会  你说怎样?
you're our last chance. What do you say?
只要举起手来
Just raise your hand up.
我们今天只要你举起手
That's all we need from you today, Chief.
只要举起手一次
Just raise your hand up one time.
给她看你可以做到的
Show her that you can do it.
给她看你能做到
Show her that you can still do it.
只要举起你的手来  大家都举起来了
Just raise your hand up. All the guys have got them up.
只要举起你的手  可以吗?
Just raise your hand up, Chief. Will you? Huh?
拜托  应该还有人不是真正的疯了!
Come on, there's got to be one guy here that's not a total fucking nut!
麦克?
Mac?
酋长!
Chief! The Chief!
瑞秋护士?  瑞秋护士!  你看!
Nurse Ratched? Nurse Ratched, look!
酋长举起手来了
Look. The Chief put his hand up.
酋长举起手来了  他投了
The Chief put his hand up. Look, he voted.
你可不可以...你可不可以把电视打开来?
Would you please turn the television set on?
酋长刚刚举起手来了
The Chief has got his hand up, right there.
酋长投票了...
The Chief voted. Now...
你能打开电视吗?
will you please turn the television set on?
麦克墨菲先生...
Mr. McMurphy...
会议已经结束  投票也结束
the meeting was adjourned, and the vote was closed.
但是结果是十票对八票
But the vote was ten to eight.
酋长他举手了!  你看!
The Chief, he's got his hand up! Look!
不是  麦克墨菲先生
No, Mr. McMurphy.
当会议结束时是九票对九票
When the meeting was adjourned, the vote was nine to nine.
拜托  你不能这样讲!
Come on, you're not gonna say that now!
你现在不能这样讲!
You're not gonna say that now!
你不可以这样混蛋...
You're gonna pull that henhouse shit, now, when the vote...
酋长刚刚投了!  结果是十比九!
The Chief just voted! It was ten to nine!
我要电视马上打开!
I want that television set turned on! Right now!
寇菲斯...
Koufax...
寇菲斯打了出去  球往外野方向飞去
Koufax kicks. He delivers.
肯定是安打
It's up the middle, it's a base hit.
理查德森跑到一垒!  向二垒跑去!
Richardson's rounding first! He's going for second!
球滚向中外野!
The ball's in to deep right center!
大卫森接住了球!
Davidson, over in the corner, cuts the ball off!
他传了出去!  理查森滑向二垒!
Here comes the throw. Richardson's around the dirt!
他滑了  到了  安全上垒!  这是个二垒安打!
He slides, he's in there. He's safe! It's a double!
他在那里  马堤尼!  看理查森站在二垒上
He's in there, Martini! Look at Richardson, he's on second base.
寇菲斯有了大麻烦!
Koufax is in big fucking trouble! Big trouble, baby!
现在是崔斯  他是下一个击球者!
All right, here's Tresh. He's the next batter!
崔斯进场  寇菲斯...
Tresh looks in. Koufax...
寇菲斯接到罗斯波洛的暗号!
Koufax gets the sign from Roseboro!
球投了出去  他挥棒落空...
He kicks once, he pumps...
好球!
It's a strike!
寇菲斯的曲球真是厉害
Koufax's curve ball is snapping off like a fucking firecracker.
现在是第二球
Here he comes with the next pitch.
崔斯挥出!  是一个左外野方向的高飞球!
Tresh swings! It's a long fly ball to deep left center!
还在飞!  中了!
It's going! It's gone!
快给我一个热狗
Somebody give me a fucking wiener before I die.
现在是伟大的麦奇・曼顿上场!  投手投了出去!
It's the great Mickey Mantle, now! Here comes the pitch!
曼顿挥棒!
Mantel swings!
这是该死的全垒打!
It's a fucking home run!
请停止这种行为
Gentlemen, stop this.
请马上停止
Stop this immediately.
你喜欢这里吗?
Do you like it here?
那个混蛋的护士!
That fucking nurse, man!
这是什么意思?
What do you mean, sir?
她不守信用
She ain't honest.
瑞秋小姐是这个机构最好的护士之一
Miss Ratched's one of the finest nurses we've got in this institution.
我不想这样说...
Well, I don't wanna break up the meeting or nothing...
但她真的很讨厌  是吧医生?
but she's something of a cunt, ain't she, Doc?
什么意思?
How do you mean that?
她常常欺骗  你懂吗?
She likes a rigged game, you know what I mean?
你知道吗?  我观察你...
Well, you know, I've been observing you here now...
已经四个礼拜了...
for the last four weeks...
但是我看不出有任何精神病的征兆
and I don't see any evidence of mental illness, at all.
我想你一直在耍我们
I think that you've been trying to put us on, all this time.
那你要我怎么做?
You know, what do you want me to do? You know.
是不是像这样?
You know what I mean? Is that it?
这够不够疯?
Is that crazy enough for you?
要我大便在地上吗?  拜托!
Want me to take a shit on the floor? Christ!
你有没有听过一句俗话"滚石不生苔"?
Have you ever heard the old saying, "A rolling stone gathers no moss"?
有啊
Yeah.
对你有任何意义吗?
Does that mean something to you?
这跟"不要在公共场合洗内衣裤"是一样道理
It's the same as "Don't wash your dirty underwear in public."
我听不懂你在说什么
I'm not sure I understand what you mean.
我比他还聪明  对吧?
I'm smarter than him, ain't I?
这大概都是这样解释的...
Well, that sort of has always meant...
移动的东西很难长东西
it's hard for something to grow on something that's moving.
你对昨天发生的事有什么感想?
How did you feel about what happened yesterday?
我想要杀掉...
I want to kill...I mean...
你们还有问题要问吗?
Do you gentlemen have any more questions?
我没有问题了  但是你大概有
I don't have any more, but perhaps you do.
你想问问题吗  麦克墨菲?
Do you have a question, McMurphy?
你猜她住在哪里?
Where do you suppose she lives?
酋长  跟我来
Chief, come on with me.
我们要告诉他们  谁才是真正的疯子
We'll show these guys who's nuts.
好了 等等
All right, wait.
站在这边
Stand right here.
好  抓住栏杆
All right. Grab the fence.
抓住栏杆这
Grab the fence here.
酋长  用力!
Right here, Chief. Strong!
用力  像这样
Strong, like this, here.
就是这样  太好了
That's it. All right.
好了  站直
Okay. Up.
你做到了
That's it.
这只手
Fine, you got it.
对  现在...推!
All right, push!
快点  鲍伯!
Come on, Bob!
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
小声点  继续走
Don't breathe on me, Club. Keep moving. Keep moving.
拜托老兄  快点走好吗?
Come on, you guys. Get the lead out, huh?
发生了什么事?
Hey, what the hell's going on here?
等一下!
Wait a minute!
停住!
Hold it!
看这多简单?
See how easy it is?
各位
Boys.
这是凯蒂
This here is Candy.
凯蒂  这就是那些伙计
Candy, this is the boys.
你们都是疯子吗?
You all crazies?
快点往下走
Let's go. Down here.
-这真是漂亮?  -往下走
-Isn't this wonderful?  -Down here.
没有问题
No problem.
就在这里
Right here.
快点  我们第一天郊游可不要迟到
Come on, we don't want to be late for our first day out.
你好!
Hello!
快点  你们在那边站着干嘛?
Come on, will ya's? What are you standing around for here?
赶快上船  凯蒂  把这些给他们
Get on board. Give them these, Candy.
等一下!  到底发生了什么事?
Hey, wait a minute! What the heck is going on here?
你们在船上干嘛?
What are you doing on this boat?
我们要去钓鱼
We're going fishing.
你们不可以去钓鱼
No, you're not going fishing.
这艘不行  你们不能用这艘去钓鱼
Not on this boat. You're not going fishing on this boat.
就是这艘船  去问布拉克船长
Oh, yeah, on this boat. Ask Captain Block.
-布拉克船长?  -是  就是布拉克船长
-Captain Block?  -Captain Block. Yes, that's right.
你们是谁?
Who are you?
我们是从...
We're from the...
州立精神病院来的...
State Mental Institution...
这是契士威克医生...
This is Dr. Cheswick...
塔波医生  佛兰迪克森医生...
Dr. Taber, Dr. Fredrickson...
史肯隆医生
Dr. Scanlon.
那个有名的史肯隆医生
The famous Dr. Scanlon.
哈定先生  毕比医生...
Mr. Harding, Dr. Bibbit...
马堤尼医生  以及...
Dr. Martini, and...
西菲德医生
Dr. Sefelt.
那你呢?  你是谁?
How about you? Who are you?
我是麦克墨菲医生  麦克墨菲
I'm Dr. McMurphy. R.P. McMurphy.
等等...
Wait, wait... Wait one second.
你不了解  我们订了这艘船
You don't understand. We chartered the boat.
准备要去钓鱼
We're going to go fishing.
仅此而已
And that's all there is to it.
你最好不要这样
You better quit on this.
不然他们会再把你送进去  知道吗?
They'll throw you in the can again, you know?
不会的  因为我们是疯子!
No, they won't. We're nuts!
他们只会送我们回农场
They'll just take us back to the feeb farm, see?
凡・西菲德  去解开缆绳
Von Sefelt, get the stern line.
塔波  去解开前缆绳
Tabes, you're at the bow.
是这条吗?
This one?
那一条!  在你脚边的
That one! The one at your feet.
赶快回来!
Get back on! Jesus!
契士威克!
Cheswick!
快点来这边!
Come here, quick!
是船长  我是说  是麦克!
Aye, aye, sir. I mean, yes, Mac!
放松点  查理  你以前开过船吗?
Take it easy, Charlie. Have you ever driven one of these things?
-开这个...  -是的
-Driven one of...  -Yeah.
没有
No, Mac.
这很好玩
Well, it's a lot of fun.
过来这边  把你的手放在方向舵上
Come on over here. Put your hands on the wheel.
-把你的手放上去  -我从来没做过
-Put your hands on.  -I've never done this.
把你的手放在舵上  这样才不会摔跤
Put your hands on the wheel so you don't fall down. All right.
只要握稳就行  就像这样
Just hold it steady right there, like that.
-握稳了吗?  -握稳了
-Steady?  -Steady, yeah.
现在往直线开
Now just go straight.
-像箭一样直  查理  -直线吗  麦克?
-Straight as an arrow, Charlie.  -Straight, Mac?
-直线就好  -但是  麦克...
-Just straight. That's right.  -But, Mac...
这不是很稳
Mac, this thing ain't too steady.
-我们去哪里  麦克?  -直线
-Where are we going, Mac?  -Straight.
开就对了!
Just go on!
这是饵
This is the bait.
小鱼
Little fishes.
死鱼
Dead fishes.
没错
That's right.
现在我们要拿这些小鱼做什么?
Now what are we gonna do with these little fishes?
-捉大鱼  -没错  马堤尼先生
-Catch big fishes.  -That's right. That's right, Mr. Martini.
鱼钩
Hooks.
拿好自己的鱼钩...
Now, hold on to your hooks...
现在要放鱼饵
Cause here are the fishes.
塔波
Tabes.
这是你的鱼
Get a fish here.
马堤尼  这是你的鱼
There, for you, Martini.
好了  现在我们每人都有一条鱼
All right, now we each one of us has got a fish.
你在笑什么  马堤尼?
What are you laughing at, Martini?
你不是笨蛋了吗?
You're not an idiot, huh?
你不是该死的疯子了  现在你是一个渔夫
You're not a goddamn looney now, boy, you're a fisherman.
现在  拿着鱼钩的底部
Now, take your bottom hook.
懂了吗?
You got it?
你拿着鱼钩...
You take it...
然后...
and you...
把它完全穿过鱼
push it all the way through.
像这样
Like that.
等一下  是穿过眼睛
Wait a second. Get it through the eyes, here.
-完全穿过这条鱼  -眼睛吗?
-Right through here.  -In the eye?
不要担心这个!  这是条死鱼  马堤尼
Don't worry about it! He's dead, Martini.
从眼球这边穿过去  这里
Jesus Christ, just put it through his eyeball, here.
就是这样
That's it.
穿过它  没错  你做到了
Crunch it right through. All right. Now you got it, see?
完全穿过这条鱼  懂吗?
Now, you just pull that baby through. You see what I mean?
然后你就像绕线圈一样缠绕
And you wrap it around. You pull this so it's a little loop.
非常好
That's very good.
那非常好  佛兰迪克森先生
That's very good, Mr. Fredrickson!
做得不错
Very good eye work.
Good eye work.
它根本不会有任何感觉的  懂吗?
That little devil's gonna not even feel the sting, is he, boy?
那个狗娘养的一定会上钩  对吧?
That son of a gun is gonna bite on you, isn't he?
你有一头很漂亮的头发
You got beautiful hair.
谢谢
Thank you.
你有...
And you got...
一双很漂亮的眼睛
beautiful eyes.
谢谢
Thank you.
比利  在干嘛啊?  对钓鱼不感兴趣吗?
Billy, what's the matter? Fishing don't grab you?
不是
They do.
到我这边来
Now, come on with me, over here.
我要把鱼竿分派给大家
I'm gonna give each and every one of ya's a rod.
太好了
All right.
这是你的
Here's your poles.
小心看着浮标  如果有动静告诉我
Now, just keep watching the tip here. If you get a strike, let me know.
懂了吗?
Understand?
来  凯蒂  兄弟们好好钓鱼!
Come on, Candy. Just keep fishing, guys!
不要叫我  除非你钓到的大到...
Don't call me unless you get something really big...
你无法处理
you can't handle yourselves.
继续钓你们的鱼!
Keep on fishing!
就是这样
That's right.
大家都到哪去了?
Where is everybody?
契士威克!  该死  我不是告诉过你...
Cheswick! Goddamn it, I told you to...
要把船保持直线吗!
steer that boat straight!
鱼!  快帮忙!
Fish! Help, help!
该死  他钓到了
Goddamn it, he's got a fish.
等一下!  塔波  我拿到了!
Hold it! Wait a minute, Tabes. I got it!
契士威克  滚回上面去!  滚到前面去!
Cheswick, get the fuck back up there! Get up there in front!
塔波  我抓到了  塔波!
Tabes, I got it, Tabes!
起来塔波  换我来弄!
Get up, Tabes, I'll get it for you!
狗娘养的  在这边!  起来塔波!
Son of a bitch, he's going over here! Get up there!
钓到了!
I got it!
-钓到了!  -让我来
-I got it!  -Give it to me!
哈定  我是船长
Hey, Harding, I'm the skipper of this boat.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
他说要走直线向箭一样直
He said to go straight out as an arrow.
可是你没有  你好像...
You're not going straight, you're kind of...
我是在走直线  现在契士  不要这样!
I'm going straight enough. Now, Chessy, stop it!
-这是我的工作!  -契士  不要烦我!
-It's my duty!  -Chessy, stop it!
你这个狗娘养的!
No, you son of a bitch!
很好  马堤尼
All right, Martini.
很好  把它钓上来!
All right, take him over!
把它钓上来!
Take him over!
就是这样!  太棒了
That's it! Now play them, boys!
你们这些狗娘养的!
You sons of bitches!
保持直线!
Keep it straight!
绕回来!
Come back this way!
安全回家了  没走失任何一个!
Home safe and sound. Didn't lose a nut!
比保龄球还好玩  你知道我的意思吧?
Beach bowling, you know what I mean?
我们钓到了!
We caught it, look!
他们要花六个月的时间来找尸体!
They're gonna be trolling this place for six months looking for dead bodies!
我认为他是危险人物
I think he's dangerous.
他没有疯...
He's not crazy...
但是他很危险
but he's dangerous.
你不认为他疯了吗?
You don't think he's crazy?
不  他并没有疯
No, he's not crazy.
桑吉医生呢?
Dr. Songee?
我想他不是个完全的精神病患
I don't think he's overly psychotic.
但他还是有病
But I still think he's quite sick.
-你认为他危险吗?  -绝对危险
-Do you think he's dangerous?  -Absolutely so.
约翰  你要怎么处理他?
Well, John, what do you want to do with him?
我想我们已经尽力了
I think we've had our turn.
我认为应该把他送回劳动农场
I'd like to send him back to the work farm, frankly.
有没有人...
Is there anybody that you have...
你的工作人员  可以...
on your staff, that could...
跟他沟通?  或许了解他
relate to him? Maybe understand him.
帮助他解决这些问题?
Help him out with some of these problems?
有趣的是他认识的人...
Well, the funny thing is that the person that he's the closest to...
却是他最讨厌的
is the one he dislikes the most.
梅儿德  就是你
That's you, Mildred.
先生们  我的意见是
Well, gentlemen, in my opinion,
如果我们把他送回潘德特...
if we send him back to Pendleton or...
或是把他送回监狱...
we send him up to Disturbed...
只是另一种逃避责任的做法而已
it's just one more way of passing on our problem to somebody else.
我们不会这样做
You know, we don't like to do that.
所以我希望能让他留在医院里
So I'd like to keep him on the ward.
我想我们可以帮助他
I think we can help him.
酋长...来
Chief, Chief, come on.
跟我来
Come with me, huh?
酋长  就是这个点
Chief, this is the spot.
就是这个点  记得吗?
Right there is the spot. Remember?
举起手来  把球放进去
Raise the hands, in the basket.
就是这样举起手来
That's it. Raise the hands up.
来吧!  疯子们  来打球吧!
All right! Let's have a little ball from you nuts in here! Here we go!
开始吧!  疯子们  让我们来玩球!
All right! Let's play some ball, nuts.
让我们动起来!
Let's make some moves!
麦克...暂停...
Hey, Mac, Mac. Time, time, time.
你有六个人在场上
You got six men on the court.
好吧  哈定离场
Harding, out of the ball game.
为什么是我呢?
Hey, why me?
因为我是教练  等一下再让你上场
Because I'm the coach. I'll put you in later.
我不相信你
I don't trust you.
麦克...我走
Mac... I'll go.
好孩子  比利  等一下让你进场
Okay, good boy, Billy. I'll put you in in a minute, all right?
好了  开始吧  哈定快攻
All right, let's play ball. Harding, break over.
马堤尼  传回来  传回来!
All right, Martini, get it back. Back!
没有人看我!  你在干嘛?
I'm in the open! What are you doing?
你把球丢往栏杆干嘛!
You threw the goddamn ball into the fence!
我的天啊  你把球丢向栏杆!
Christ Almighty, you threw the ball into the fence!
那边没有人!  我们在比赛!
There's nobody there! We're playing ball!
快点继续进行
All right, come on, get in the game.
防守  大家都要尽力!
Defense, nobody's doing nothing here!
-看在上帝的份上!  -麦克  没人防我!
-For Christ's sake!  -Hey, Mac, I'm open! I'm open!
哈定传回来  传回来给我  哈定!  这里
All right, Harding, give it back. Back to me, Harding! Here.
哈定  没人防我  传给我
I'm open. Harding, will you give me the ball?
-不要再运球了  真该死!  -我拿到了!
-Stop dribbling the goddamn ball!  -I got it!
哈定  这边
Harding, over here.
该死  我站在...
Oh, for Christ's sake. I'm standing...
-你们都被防着!  -没人守我!
-You were covered!  -I was open!
-给我球啊  -他们全都在...
-Just give me the ball. -They're making all over the...
没人守我  球给我
I was open. Give me the ball.
有人守你  麦克
You were covered, Mac.
没有人守我  来人接球啊!
I wasn't covered. Somebody get back!
把球给我!  给我!
Give it to me! Give it to me!
酋长!  太棒了  放进去!
Chief! Thatta baby, put it in!
过去那边!
Get down there!
过去那里  酋长!  太好了.
Get down there, Chief! All right, all right.
绕过去  酋长!
Get around, Chief!
不对  是那边  酋长!
No, no, no. Get down there, Chief!
比赛继续进行!
The ball's in play! Ball's in play!
去你妈的  你一定疯了
Oh, fuck that shit! You got to be crazy.
-没人防守!  -比赛继续进行!
-Man, that doesn't go!  -Get that ball in play!
酋长  投篮!
Come on, Chief. Put it in!
打得真好!
What a ball club!
麦克墨菲  不要靠着墙
McMurphy, get off the side.
-走开!  -该死!
-Come on, move it, man!  -Hey, dammit!
来啊
Quick! Come on, go ahead.
Go ahead.
打下去啊
总有一天我会在外面见到你  你懂我意思吧?
I'll be seeing you on the outside. You know what I mean?
到那一天...
By the time you get out of here...
你会老到不能动
you'll be too old to even get it up.
68天  小子
Sixty-eight days, buddy.
68天
Sixty-eight days.
你都不知道你在说什么吧  68天?
What the fuck you talking about, 68 days?
那是服刑
That's in jail, sucker.
你还是不知道你在那里  是吧?
You still don't know where you're at?
我会是在哪里  华盛顿?
Yeah, where am I at, Washington?
跟我们在一起
With us, baby, you're with us.
你会待到我们释放你
And you're gonna stay with us until we let you go.
你对这组有话要说吗  麦克墨菲?
Do you want to say something to the group, Mr. McMurphy?
我想知道为什么没有人告诉我...
I'd like to know why none of the guys never told me that you...
必须经过你瑞秋护士...
Miss Ratched...
还有医生的准许
and the doctors could keep me here
才能释放呢
till you're good and ready to turn me loose.
我想知道这件事
That's what I'd like to know.
很好  蓝道  这是个好的开始
Fine, Randall, that's a good start.
有没有人可以回答麦克墨菲先生的问题?
Would anyone care to answer Mr. McMurphy?
回答什么?
Answer what?
你听到了  哈定
You heard me, Harding.
你让我去骚扰瑞秋护士...
You let me go on hassling Nurse Ratched here...
而却不告诉我该如何被释放!
knowing how much I had to lose and you never told me nothing!
麦克  等一下
Now, Mac, wait a minute.
我也不清楚...
Wait a minute, I didn't know anything about how much...
-屁话!  -等一下
-Shit!  -Wait a minute. Listen.
听着...
Now, look...
我是自愿进来  我并没有犯罪
I'm voluntary here, see? I'm not committed.
我不需要待在这里  我是说我可以随时回家
I don't have to stay here. I mean, I can go home anytime I want.
你可以随时回家?
You can go home anytime you want?
-没错  -你在耍我!
-That's it.  -You're bullshitting me!
他在耍我  对吧?
He's bullshitting me, right?
不  蓝道  他说的是实话
No, Randall, he's telling you the truth.
事实上有很多人是罪犯
As a matter of fact, there are very few men here who are committed.
譬如  布鲁登先生
There's Mr. Bromden.
塔波先生
Mr. Taber.
再加上你
Some of the chronics, and you.
契士威克?
Cheswick?
你是自愿进来的吗?
You're voluntary?
史肯隆?
Scanlon?
比利  看在老天的份上  你一定是罪犯  对吧?
Billy, for Christ's sake, you must be committed, right?
不...
No, no, no...
你还很年轻!
You're just a young kid!
在这里干嘛?  你应该到外面去...
What are you doing here? You ought to be out in a convertible...
溜鸟  约会  找乐子
bird-dogging chicks and banging beaver.
你在这里干嘛?
What are you doing here, for Christ's sake?
这有什么好笑?
What's so funny about that?
我是说你们一直抱怨这个地方...
Jesus, I mean, you guys do nothing but complain about how you can't...
但是你们没有勇气走出这里
stand it in this place here, and then you haven't got the guts to walk out?
你们以为你们是疯子吗?
What do you think you are, for Christ's sake? Crazy or something?
你们不是!
Well, you're not. You're not!
你们跟街上的混蛋
You're no crazier than the average asshole
没有什么两样
out walking around on the streets.
就是这样
And that's it.
我的天啊  我真不敢相信!
Jesus Christ, I can't believe it!
这是个很好的挑战  蓝道
Those are very challenging observations you made, Randall.
我相信有人会想对此提出意见
I'm sure some of the men would like to comment.
史肯隆?
Mr. Scanlon?
我想要知道为什么宿舍在白天和周末
I want to know why the dorm is locked
要锁起来
in the daytime and on weekends.
我想要知道关于香烟
I would like to know about our cigarettes.
瑞秋小姐  可不可以给我烟  拜托
May I have my cigarettes, please, Miss Ratched?
坐下  契士威克先生  等轮到你再说话
You sit down, Mr. Cheswick, and wait your turn.
快点坐下!
Go ahead, sit down!
关于宿舍的问题  史肯隆先生...
To answer your question about the dorm, Mr. Scanlon...
你知道...
You know very well...
如果不锁门的话
that if we left the door open,
你们会在早餐之后又回去睡觉
you'd just go right back to bed after breakfast.
对吧?
Am I right?
那又怎么样?
So what?
瑞秋小姐  可不可以给我香烟?
May I have my cigarettes, please, Miss Ratched?
不要管香烟了  契士威克
Forget the cigarettes, Cheswick.
这不是很重要的  坐下  好吗?
Cigarettes are not important. Sit down, will you?
天啊!
For Christ's sake!
香烟!
Cigarettes!
记得吗  史肯隆先生  我们讨论过很多次...
Remember, Mr. Scanlon, we've discussed many times...
跟别人生活在一起  有助于治疗的效果
that time spent in the company of others is very therapeutic.
一个人生活会有疏离感
While time spent brooding alone only increases a feeling of separation.
你记得  对吧?
You remember that, don't you?
你是说...
Do you mean to say...
单独待着就是病?
it's sick to want to be off by yourself?
瑞秋小姐?
Miss Ratched?
契士威克先生  你坐下!
Mr. Cheswick, you sit down!
-但是我想知道...  -坐下  契士威克
-Yes, but I want to know about...  -Sit down, Mr. Cheswick.
我想要..
I want to...
给他一根香烟吧哈定
Give him a cigarette, will you, Harding?
这是我最后一枝
It's my last one.
你在说谎  为什么你不给他一枝香烟呢?
That's a fucking lie. Why don't you give him a cigarette?
我不是做慈善的
Look, I'm not running a charity ward, see?
拜托!
Come on!
听着  我不想要他的烟
Look, I don't want his cigarettes.
我也不想要他的  他的  或是他的...
And I don't want his, or his, or his...
或是他的  他的  还有他的...
or his, or his, or his...
甚至是你的
Or even yours.
你懂吗?
Do you understand that?
我要我的烟  瑞秋小姐!
I want my cigarettes, Miss Ratched!
我要我的烟!
I want my cigarettes!
我要我的烟  瑞秋小姐!
I want mine, Miss Ratched!
你有什么权利...
What gives you the damn right...
去把我们的烟扣留下来摆在你的桌上...
to keep our cigarettes piled up on your desk...
当你高兴的时候才会发一包?
and to squeeze out a pack only when you feel like it, huh?
-瑞秋小姐!  -哈定先生!
-Miss Ratched!  -Mr. Harding!
抱歉...
Oh, I'm sorry...
你让我感到惊讶
You surprise me.
我只是一时失去理智  很抱歉
I lost my head. I'm sorry.
我不是故意的...
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to...
真的很抱歉  我忘了
I'm really very sorry. I just forgot.
我不是故意的  真的很抱歉  只是忘了
I didn't mean to. I'm really very sorry. Just forgot.
没关系
It's all right.
瑞秋小姐!
Miss Ratched!
契士威克先生干嘛?
Yes, Mr. Cheswick?
我在问你问题!
I asked you a question!
我听到你的问题了  契士威克先生...
I heard your question, Mr. Cheswick...
只要安静下来  我就会回答你的问题
and I will answer your question as soon as you've calmed down.
安静下来了吗  契士威克先生?
Are you calm, Mr. Cheswick?
-是的  -很好
-I'm calm.  -Good.
你们都知道麦克墨菲先生...
Now, as you all know, Mr. McMurphy...
在这里开了一家小型赌场
has been running a small gambling casino in our tub room.
你们大部份的烟都输给了麦克墨菲先生...
Now, most of you lost all your cigarettes to Mr. McMurphy...
再加上小额的金钱
not to mention a tidy sum of money to Mr. McMurphy.
所以这就是为什么...
And that's why...
你们的福利被暂停了...
your tub room privileges have been suspended...
而你们的烟则受到管制
and your cigarettes have been rationed.
马堤尼先生?
Mr. Martini?
我们如何把我们的钱赢回来?
How are we gonna win our money back?
你不可能把钱赢回来  马堤尼先生
You're not going to win your money back, Mr. Martini.
已经不可能了
That's all over.
若你们一开始就遵守规则的话...
If you had obeyed the rules in the first place...
就不会输掉你们的钱
you wouldn't have lost your money.
坐下  大家坐下!  先生们!  坐下!
Sit down, gentlemen! Sit down, gentlemen! Sit down!
规则?
Rules?
去你妈的规则  瑞秋小姐!
Piss on your fucking rules, Miss Ratched!
你坐下  契士威克?
Sit down, will you, Cheswick?
我要慎重的告诉你一件事  瑞秋小姐!
I want you to know something right here and now, Miss Ratched!
-不要把我当小孩子!  -你坐下!
-I ain't no little kid! I ain't no little kid!  -You sit down!
你一直控制我的烟  像是控制小孩的饼干...
When you're gonna have cigarettes kept from me like cookies...
我要现在解决这件事!  对不对麦克?
And I want something done! Ain't that right, Mac?
没错!  你能不能先坐下?
That's right! Will you sit down?
不  我不坐!
No, I won't! I won't!
我要现在解决!
I want something done!
-坐下!  -我要现在解决!
-Sit down!  -I want something done!
我要现在解决!
I want something done!
-拿去!  -我要现在解决!
-Here!  -I want something done!
该死  契士威克  给你!
Goddamn it, Cheswick, here!
安静下来!
Hey, calm down!
你能不能不要烦他?  华盛顿  他会安静的!
Why don't you leave him alone, Washington? He's gonna be all right!
紧急情况...
Emergency...
34B
34-B.
我要打断你的脖子!
I'll break your fucking back!
不要挣扎了  麦克!  已经结束了  麦克墨菲!
Forget it, Mac! It's all over, McMurphy!
渥伦!
Warren!
能不能让一下?  我们需要这张椅子
Would you move, please? We need this chair.
坐到那边去就好了
Just move right over there, okay.
伯尔登先生又回来了
I see we have Mr. Bromden back. Yeah, okay.
-麦克墨菲先生  你还好吗?  -我很好
-How do you do, Mr. McMurphy?  -I do real fine.
我知道你没有做错事
I know you didn't do anything wrong. Just sit down.
我们不会伤害你的  先坐下
We're not going to hurt you. Sit down, right here.
就是这样
That's it.
护士  这是契士威克先生  他余怒未息
Nurse, this is Mr. Cheswick. He's a little upset.
非常感谢你
Okay, fine. Thank you very much.
-你会好的  契士威克先生  -是的
-You'll be okay, Mr. Cheswick.  -Yes.
你能不能看住这三个?
Would you keep an eye on these two?
先生们  吃药吧
Would you please take these, gentlemen?
他听不见
He can't hear nothing.
安静下来  契士  好吗?
Calm down, Ches, will you?
契士威克先生  请跟我来
Mr. Cheswick, would you please follow me?
契士威克先生?
Mr. Cheswick?
-不!  -没有人会伤害你的  来吧
-No!  -Nobody's gonna hurt you, come on.
-不!  -没有关系的
-No!  -It'll be all right. Come on.
来吧  没有关系的  没有人会伤害你的
You're all right. No one's gonna hurt you.
不  让我一个人待着!
No, leave me alone!
-放松点好吗  来吧!  -不!
-Take it easy on yourself. Come on!  -No!
麦克!  麦克!
Mac! Mac!
不!
No!
快点  快啊
Come on. Come on, now. Come on.
-快  -不!
-Come on.  -No!
我没有做错事!
I didn't do nothing!
麦克!
Mac!
-来吧!  -不  我不要去!  我不要去!
-Come on.  -I won't go! I don't want to go!
要口香糖吗?
Want some gum?
谢谢
Thank you.
果汁口味
Juicy Fruit.
你这个超级大混蛋  酋长
You sly son of a bitch, Chief.
你可以听到  对吧?
Can you hear me, too?
当然!
Yeah, you bet!
我真该死  酋长!
Well, I'll be goddamned, Chief!
他们一直以为你是又笨又聋的
And they all, they all think you're deaf and dumb.
我的老天啊!
Jesus Christ!
你愚弄他们的  酋长
You fooled them, Chief.
你把他们全部骗得团团转!
You fooled them. You fooled them all!
该死的!
Goddamn you!
我们在这里干嘛  酋长?
What are we doing in here, Chief?
我们在这个该死的地方干嘛?
What's us, two guys, doing in this fucking place?
我们离开这里吧...
Let's get out of here...
出去
Out.
去加拿大?
Canada?
加拿大
Canada.
在那些人渣发现以前  我们早就跑了
We'll be there before these sons of bitches know what hit them.
听我这一次
Listen to Randall on this one.
麦克墨菲先生?
Mr. McMurphy?
请跟我来
Please follow me.
就你跟我  酋长
You and me, Chief.
现在是休息时间  放轻松点
Take a cigarette break, boys. Easy.
这样就好了
I'll be fine.
请坐起来
Would you sit up, please?
-乐意之至  -非常好
-I'd love to.  -Thatta boy.
鞋子上可能会湿湿的  懂我意思吗?
There might be a little fluid in them boots, you know what I mean, boys?
只是尿了一点
Just a little leak.
会满亮的...
A light shine, boys, and...
把样品送给瑞秋小姐
send the specimen to Nurse Ratched.
把口香糖吐出来...
All right, out with your gum...
把口香糖吐出来
Out with your gum.
这不会痛  一下就过去了
Okay, this won't hurt, and it'll be over in just a moment.
-那是什么?  -导电膏
-What's that?  -Conductant.
一点就够了
A little dab will do you.
对吧  杰克森先生?
Right, Mr. Jackson?
张开嘴...
Open your mouth...
-这是什么?  -是防止你咬到舌头...
-What's that?  -This'll keep you from biting your tongue...
咬紧它
Now just bite down on it.
就是这样  咬紧它
That's right. Just bite down.
咬紧
Now, bite down on it.
准备好了吗?
Are you ready?
开始了
Here we go.
深呼吸
Now, one big breath.
非常好
Very good.
大家现在开始吧  不会很久的
Gentlemen, I'd like to begin today. It shouldn't take too long.
吉姆?
Jim?
据我所知...
It's been brought to my attention...
你把你的药给了佛兰迪克森先生
that you've been giving Mr. Fredrickson your medication.
是真的吗?
Is that true?
没有
No, ma'am.
吉姆?
Jim?
你到底有没有把你的药给佛兰迪克森先生...
Are you giving your medication to Mr. Fredrickson...
有没有?
or are you not?
你们这些人渣  疯子  神经病
How about it, you creeps, you lunatics, mental defectives.
吹牛大王兰道尔重新登场
Let's hear it for Bullgoose Randall, back in action.
很漂亮的衬衫
Nice shirt, Cheseroo.
看看你们的脸!
Look at the faces on you!
看看!
Look at you!
真是丑恶
The feeb's brigade, you ding-a-lings?
神经病联盟又在一起了
The mental defective league in formation.
你好吗  瑞秋护士?  很高兴回来
How are you, Nurse Ratched? I'm happy to be back.
我们很高兴你回来  兰道尔
We're happy to have you back, Randall.
谢谢
Thank you.
你今天要休息还是要加入我们?
Would you like to rest today, or would you like to join the group?
我很乐意加入大家...
I'd love to join the group...
很乐意...
I'd like...
我很乐意  麦德尔
I'm proud to join the group, Mildred.
你感觉如何  麦克?
How's it going, Mac?
非常好  小比利  相当不错
Perfect, Billy Boy, absolutely perfect.
他们每天给我一万瓦  我...
They was giving me 10,000 watts a day, you know, and I'm...
现在很烧
hot to trot.
下一个我干的女人
The next woman takes me on
会像游戏机一样亮起来...
is gonna light up like a pinball machine...
真是太值得了!
and pay off in silver dollars!
非常有趣  兰道尔...
That's an amusing thought, Randall...
当你进来的时候吉姆正在发言
but when you came in we were talking to Jim.
他吃药的习惯有问题...
He has a problem with his medication...
现在回到主题
and we'd like to get back to that.
我一点也不介意  瑞秋护士  我现在...
Oh, I don't. I don't mind at all, Nurse Ratched, I'm...
就像小狗一样乖...
gentle as a puppy dog and...
请继续  谢谢
Please proceed. Thank you.
大家晚安  明天见
Good night, gentlemen. See you in the morning.
亲爱的  我是麦克
Yeah, baby, it's Mac.
就今晚了
It's on tonight.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
别担心  找一辆车
Don't worry about it. Get a car.
我不管  宝贝  如果要的话偷一辆来
I don't give a shit, baby. Steal it if you have to.
我必须要走了!  我必须要走了!
I gotta go! I gotta go!
不要忘了带酒来
Don't forget to bring some booze.
对
Right.
再见
Bye.
酋长  我受不了
Chief, I can't take it no more.
我要逃走
I gotta get out of here.
我不能  就是不能
I can't. I just can't.
比你想的要简单  酋长
It's easier than you think, Chief.
对你更是这样  你比我还壮
For you, maybe. You're a lot bigger than me.
酋长  你像树一样的巨大
Why, Chief, you're about as big as a goddamn tree trunk.
我的父亲真的很壮
My poppa's real big.
他随心所欲
He did like he pleased.
所以每个人都利用他
That's why everybody worked on him.
上一次我看到他的时候
The last time I've seen my father
他因为喝太多酒而瞎了
he was blind in the cedars from drinking.
每一次他把酒瓶放进嘴里...
And every time he put the bottle to his mouth...
不是他喝酒
he don't suck out of it.
而是酒喝他  直到他有了很多皱纹...
It sucks out of him until he'd shrunk so...
皮肤也变黄  连狗都不认识他
wrinkled and yellow, even the dogs don't know him.
他就是这样死的  对吧?
Killed him, huh?
我没有说他们杀掉他
I'm not saying they killed him.
他们只是利用他  就像他们利用你一样
They just worked on him, the way they're working on you.
他们来了  酋长
There they are, Chief.
他们来了  他们来这儿了
There they are. They're here.
在这里!
Over here. That's it!
麦克墨菲停止那个疯狂的行为...
McMurphy, stop all this Holy Roller shit...
赶快滚回床上  你懂吗?
and get your ass back in bed. Do you understand?
神聆听了我的祷告  特寇
My prayers have been answered, Turkle.
所以来看看
Come on and see.
20块钱...
You'd take $20...
别说出去  可以吗  特寇?
to get down on your knees and pray, wouldn't you, Turkle?
没有办法  没有办法
No, it don't send me, don't send me.
-不行吗?  -对我来说没差
-It don't?  -Don't do nothing to me, no.
你知道还有更多的...
Well, you know there'll be more...
我是说  他们会带两瓶酒来...
I mean, they'll be bringing a couple of bottles with them, and...
继续说下去  老兄  继续说下去  但是...
You're getting closer, brother. You're getting closer, but...
应该还有比酒更好的  对吧?
they're gonna be sharing more than just bottles, ain't they?
-你懂我的意思吗?  -当然
-You know what I mean?  -Yeah, sure.
-我懂你的意思  -你懂我的意思吗?
-I know what you mean.  -You understand what I mean?
我懂你的意思
Yeah, I understand what you mean.
-尽管开口  -老兄  我什么都没看见
-Anything you say, Turkle.  -I'm on my knees, brother.
-我什么都没看见  -太好了
-I'm on my knees.  -Yeah, all right, all right.
-我来帮她们一下  -感激不尽
-Let me just give them a hand here.  -I appreciate that.
女士们!
Ladies!
谢谢  这都归你了  特寇先生
Oh, thank you. I believe this is your department, Mr. Turkle.
-没错  帮我一下  -萝丝  你好吗?
-Hi, there! Give me a hand.  -Hi, Rose, how you doing?
乐意之至
Love to give you a hand.
小声一点
Keep it down. Keep it down.
-我的裤子破了  -小声点!
-I split my pants.  -Keep it down!
-给我  全部都给我  -能不能安静点!
-Give it to me. Give it all to me.  -You got to keep it down!
看起来像是我的高中
This looks like my high school.
我要这个
Oh, hey, I take that.
-我要那个理发厅的椅子  -你可以拿走
-The barber chair.  -You may have it.
那是我的了
It is mine, mine.
你可以拿走  亲爱的
You can have it. You can have it, honey.
-看看这些水管  -你的地方真不错
-Take a load of these tubs.  -It's a real nice place you got here.
我可不可以洗个澡?
Hey, can I take a bath?
当然可以
Sure, you can take a bath. Sure.
只要不要淹死就好
Just don't drown your pretty little self.
你知道吗...
You know...
萝丝曾跟疯子结婚  是在伯特镇上
Rose was married to a maniac once, up in Beaverton.
真的吗  小姐?
Oh, really, miss?
发生什么事?
What seemed to be the problem?
没发生什么事  只是他常常放青蛙在我胸罩里
Oh, nothing, he used to put frogs in my bra all the time.
非常有趣
Very interesting.
萝丝对医院的设备非常感兴趣
Rose is very interested in hospitals, and hospital facilities.
-有吗  -当然有
-I am?  -Yes. Oh, yes, you are.
-我要带凯蒂去...  -你们去哪里?
-I'm going to take Miss Candy...  -Where you going?
我带凯蒂去散步
I'm gonna take Candy for a stroll.
懂了
I got you, I got you.
-不要太大声就好  -好吧  不准偷看
-But just don't make too much noise.  -Oh, no, not a peep, not a peep.
来吧宝贝  到这边来
Now, you come over here, baby, right over here.
别担心凯蒂  现在坐下来轻松一下
Don't worry about Candy, honey. Sit down and relax.
醒来吧
Wake up, boys.
醒来
Wake up.
吃药时间到了
It's medication time.
Medication time.
夜之魂出现了
The nighttime spirits are here.
蓝道来说再见...
It's Randall to say goodbye...
在旁边是可爱的凯蒂天使
and get you high, and nighttime angel, Candy.
是的  马堤尼先生  这是只复活节兔子
That's right, Mr. Martini, there is an Easter bunny.
靠过来  大家一起来麦克墨菲先生的...
Round the side, boys, join Mr. McMurphy...
联谊室
in the executive lounge, please.
靠过来
Round the side.
太棒了
It's gonna be so great.
你喜欢喝酒  对吧查理?
You like a nip, don't you, Charles?
-我们会有麻烦吧  -根本不会!
-We gonna get in trouble.  -No trouble at all!
这是比利  无可比拟的俱乐部  14...
It's Billy the Club of the fabulous and fantastic 14...
-这里发生了什么事  -特寇先生...
-What the hell's going on?  -Mr. Turkle...
这不是在找麻烦吗!
Ain't this a bitch!
麦克墨菲  你是不是要我被抄鱿鱼?
McMurphy, what you trying to do? Get my ass really fired, man?
快从那边滚开
Come on, get your ass out of here. Come on.
我们只是在办派对
We're just having a party.
去他妈的派对!  这里不是夜总会  这是医院
Party, my ass! This ain't no nightclub, this is a hospital.
这是我的工作
Man, this is my fucking job.
我不管  这是我该死的工作
I don't give a damn, this is my fucking job.
该死!  督察来了!
Oh, shit! The supervisor!
赶快滚进去
Come on, get your asses back in there.
快点!
Come on. Come on there!
那个人渣到哪里去了?  他在里面吗?
Where is that no-talking son of a bitch? Is he in there?
赶快进去
Good. Come on.
特寇先生?
Mr. Turkle?
他死哪去了?  为什么不回答?
Where the hell is he? Why doesn't he answer?
他去鬼混了
He's jerking off somewhere.
去他妈的鬼混  混蛋!
Ain't nobody jerking off nowhere, motherfucker!
特寇  你在这边干嘛?  出去回答她
Turkle, what the fuck are you doing here? Go out there and talk to her.
跟你做同样的事情  混蛋  躲起来!
Doing the same fucking thing you're doing in here, hiding!
你好  女士
Yes, ma'am?
一切正常吗  特寇先生?
Everything all right, Mr. Turkle?
一切正常  女士
Oh, everything is just fine, ma'am.
很好
Just fine. Just fine.
谁在里面?
Who's there?
没有人啊
Ain't nobody in there.
请开门
Please open that door.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉  但是...
I'm sorry, ma'am, but...
你知道男人在晚上是很寂寞的...
you know, a man gets awfully lonesome at night...
你了解吗?
You understand what I mean, don't you?
你懂的?  我确定你懂的
You understand? I'm sure you understand.
我要那个女人马上离开这里
I want that woman off this ward, immediately.
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
-天啊!  -特寇先生  她走了吗?
-Jesus!  -Mr. Turkle, is she gone?
妈的!  对  她走了  我也是...
Shit! Yes, she's gone, and so am I...
躲在后面的出来  全都躺回床上去
so get your behinds on out of here and go back to bed.
快点  动作快点  快点!
Go ahead, move it, move it! Move it!
-该死  我就知道会有麻烦!  -快点  快走!
-I knew we were in trouble!  -Come on, let's go!
动动你的屁股!  快点!
You and your teddy bear ass! Move them on out of here!
快!
Come on, come on!
-凯蒂?  -快点  凯蒂!
-Candy?  -Come on, Candy!
天杀的!
Jesus Christ!
特寇  我真的很抱歉
Mr. Turkle, I'm really sorry.
去告诉我那些人渣朋友  滚出去!
Tell the fucking friends of mine to get out!
-滚出去!  -我真的很抱歉
-Get out!  -I'm really sorry.
你真的是...
What are you...?
该死  快滚!
What the fuck...? Get out of here!
快滚  这是我的工作  被你们搞砸了
Please get out, this is my job! You fucking it up! You understand?
滚出去!
Get out!
你这个人渣!  快点滚出去!
Get out of here, you slim motherfucker!
去你妈的!
Fuck it!
晚安  不要吃太多饼干
Good night, good night, don't let the cooties bite.
从诊疗部门弄来的  我是从...
Right out of the shock department. I got it from...
我从瑞秋的推车上拿来的
I got it from Ratched's charts.
喝吧喝吧  小心点
Right. There you go, there you go. Easy now.
不要一次喝完!
Don't take it all at once!
给别人留点  给你
Let's try a little over here. There you go.
我们走吧
Let's go.
我走了  酋长
I'll have to be the one, Chief.
麦克  发生了什么事?
Hey, Mac, what's going on?
代尔...
Well, Dale...
蓝道准备逃了
Lord Randall is stepping down one.
佛兰迪克森
Fredrickson.
吉姆
Jimmy.
你不跟我说再见吗  麦克?
Aren't you gonna say goodbye to me, Mac?
当然会  再见  查理
Sure, I'm gonna say goodbye to you, Charles.
谢谢你  麦克
Thank you, Mac.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我不会忘记你的
I'll never forget you.
没关系  查理  没关系
Settle down, Charles, all right.
比利  怎么了?
Hey, Billy, what's wrong?
怎么了嘛?
Billy, for Christ's sake?
到底怎么了?
What's the matter?
我会很想你的...
I'm gonna miss you very...
麦克
very, very much, Mac.
那你跟我们一起来吧?
Why don't you come with us, then?
你以为我不想吗?
Think I don't want to?
那来吧  一起走
Well, so come on then, let's go.
没那么容易
Well, it's not that easy.
我还没准备好
I'm not ready yet.
这样吧  等我们...
Tell you what we'll do...
到了加拿大后寄明信片给你...
When I get to Canada, I'll write you a postcard...
上面会附住址
and I'll put my address on it.
这样你就能知道...
That way when you're ready, you'll...
到哪里去找我
you'll know where to go.
怎么样?
What do you say?
她会跟你去吗?
She going with you?
凯蒂?
Candy?
你到那边会看到她  她要跟我们一起走
Yeah, she'll be there when you get there. She's going with us.
你会跟她结婚吗?
Are you gonna marry her?
不会的  我们只是好朋友
No, we're just good friends.
怎么了?
Why?
没什么
Nothing.
别说"没什么"  告诉我  怎么了?
Don't "nothing" me, all right? What is it?
太晚了
It's too late.
你想约她吗?
Do you want a date with her?
我的天啊  我一定是疯了才待在这边!
Jesus, I must be crazy to be in a looney bin like this!
约会?
Date, huh?
一定是很快就结束
Well, it'll have to be a fast date, I'll tell you that.
不是现在
Not now.
不是现在?
Not now?
那什么时候呢?
When, then?
等我有周末休假的时候
When I have a free weekend.
你现在很忙吗?
You busy right now, are you?
你有事要做吗?
You got something to do right now?
-现在你有事要做吗?  -不...
-You go something to do?  -No...
那不要告诉我你还没准备好
Good, then don't talk to me about when you're ready. Yeah, yeah.
-就是现在  -不
-Ready and everything like that.  -No.
凯蒂  过来一下
Candy, come here a minute.
凯蒂  来认识一下著名的比利
Candy, I want you to meet the famous Billy.
你去把他找来
Go get him, will you?
把他捉出来
Go get him. Get him out of there.
去把比利捉出来
I want you to get a hold of Billy.
你只要做这件小小的事
All you gotta do is this one little thing.
-那孩子很可爱对吧?  -对啊
-The kid's cute, isn't he?  -Yeah.
你只要从头到尾想着我就好
Think of me the whole time.
现在来的是
There he is.
大帅哥比利!
Billy the Club!
我赌25块...
I got $25...
赌注是你可以让这个女人疯狂!
that says you are gonna burn this woman down!
凯蒂宝贝...
Candy, baby...
我爱你
I love ya.
把钟敲响吧
Hurl the ringer.
放松点!  退后!
Take it easy! Back on!
不...我来表演一些扑克牌魔术
No, no, no, I'll show you some card tricks.
你们还没看过这个西班牙魔术
You ain't seen the Spanish deck yet.
这会有更多的乐趣
That's 40 percent more torture.
我把这副漂亮的扑克牌送给你
I'm gonna present you with this fine deck of cards for playing.
这不会太久  萝丝  你懂我的意思吗?
This ain't gonna take long, Rose, you know what I mean?
等我们到了加拿大...
When we get to Canada...
成何体统!
Out of sight, man!
Out of sight!
-早安  -早安
-Good morning.  -Good morning.
渥伦先生...
Mr. Warren...
关上窗户  锁上纱窗
close the window, and lock the screen.
好的
Right.
米勒先生  带这个女人出去
Mr. Miller, show this woman the way out of the hospital.
乐意之至
Gladly.
来吧女士  走吧
Come on, lady, let's go.
-你要回家  -哪里?
-You're going home.  -Where?
放开  史肯隆
Let her go, Scanlon.
你要回家
You're going home.
-华盛顿先生?  -是的  瑞秋小姐
-Mr. Washington?  -Yes, Miss Ratched.
清点人数
Make sure no one is missing.
马上
Will do.
-麦克?  -来吧  史肯隆  走
-Mac?  -Come on, Scanlon, let's move.
-所有人都出去!  -动作快点!
-Everybody out of here!  -Come on, move it out!
快点  拜托!
Come on, move it!
马堤尼  赶快起来!
Martini, get your butt up! Come on, up!
赶快滚到那边去
All right, Colonel, get your dead ass up there!
到底发生什么事?  快出去!
What the hell's going on here? Come on, move out!
瑞秋小姐?
Miss Ratched?
佛兰迪克森  你在干什么?
Fredrickson, what are you doing?
你往哪走?  回来!
Where you going? Back out of here!
快走!  走!
Let's go! Come on, move it!
塔波  快点起来
Taber, get up. Come on.
我说起来!
I said, get up!
滚到那边去  麦克墨菲...
All right, move it back there! McMurphy...
滚过来  把德克拉也带来
get your ass over here, and bring Dracula with you.
不要动  巴西尼!
Stay right there, Bancini!
-瑞秋小姐?  -是的
-Miss Ratched?  -Yes.
看来只有比利・毕比不见了
It looks like Billy Bibbit's the only one missing.
比利?
Billy?
谢谢你  华盛顿先生
Thank you, Mr. Washington.
比利・毕比离开医院了吗?
Did Billy Bibbit leave the grounds of the hospital, gentlemen?
我要你们回答问题
I want an answer to my question.
他是不是离开了医院?
Did he leave the grounds of the hospital?
-华盛顿先生?  -是的
-Mr. Washington?  -Yes.
毕波小姐  去检查每个房间
Miss Pilbow, check all the rooms.
-渥伦先生?  -是
-Mr. Warren?  -Yes.
你从澡堂开始
You start with the tub room.
马堤尼先生?
Mr. Martini?
可不可以把帽子还给我?
May I have my cap, please?
我的帽子!
My cap!
那儿
There.
谢谢
Thank you.
瑞秋小姐
Miss Ratched.
我可以解释
I can explain everything.
请解释  比利
Please do, Billy.
解释所有的事
Explain everything.
所有吗?
Everything?
你不觉得羞耻吗?
Aren't you ashamed?
我不觉得
No, I'm not.
比利  我担心的是...
You know, Billy, what worries me is...
你妈妈能够接受这个事实吗?
how your mother's going to take this.
你...
Well, you...
不需要...
don't have to...
告诉她  瑞秋小姐
tell her, Miss Ratched.
我不需要告诉她?
I don't have to tell her?
但我们是老朋友了  你知道的
Your mother and I are old friends, you know that.
请...
Please...
不要...
don't...
告诉我妈妈
tell my mother.
你不觉得应该在
Don't you think you should have thought of that
带那女人进去之前...
before you took that woman...
先想清楚吗?
in that room?
不...
No, no.
我没有
I didn't.
她硬拖你进去的吗?
You mean, she dragged you in there by force?
是的
She did.
所有人都有份
Everybody did.
所有人?  到底是谁?
Everybody? Who did?
你告诉我是谁做的!
You tell me who did!
墨菲
Murphy.
瑞秋小姐...
Miss Ratched...
请不要...
please don't...
-渥伦先生?  -告诉我妈妈  拜托
-Mr. Warren?  -tell my mother, please.
你能不能让他们去洗干净  然后收拾好一切
Would you see that the men are washed and ready for the day.
瑞秋小姐  求你...求你了...
Miss Ratched, please...please...
-华盛顿先生?  -是
-Mr. Washington?  -Yes?
-送比利到史贝菲的办公室  -不!
-Put Billy in Dr. Spivey's office.  -No!
在医生来之前看住他
Stay with him till the doctor arrives.
走!  快点  马堤尼  快走!
Move it! Come on, Martini, get on!
拜托大家往那走
Hey, that way, please. Please, gentlemen.
快点走  快走
Let's go, come on. Come on, you guys. What is this?
我们走吧
Let's go.
那是什么?
Hey, what the hell is that?
麦克墨菲  你在干嘛?
McMurphy, what the hell are you doing?
华盛顿  快来长廊!  马上!
Washington, to the day room! Lmmediately!
把钥匙摆下  没有人会受伤
Put down those keys and nobody gets hurt.
跟酋长一起远离窗户
Move away from the window and take that damn Chief with you.
快点  快走!
Come on, let's go!
让我过去!
Let me through!
不要挡路  麦克墨菲!
Out of the way, McMurphy!
快点  清场!
Come on, clear it!
把这些人赶出去!
Get these people out of here!
比利!
Oh, Billy!
你们能不能让开一下?
Will you guys clear the door?
全都出去!  全部都出去!
Everybody out! Out! Everybody out!
快点  该死的!
Come on, goddammit!
安静下来!
Now calm down!
我们现在能做的就是回到日常工作
The best thing we can do is go on with our daily routine.
好吗?
All right?
别这样!  麦克!
Don't! Mac!
麦克!  不要!
Mac! No!
赌注都下好了
And the bets are placed.
这个是塔波  契士  马堤尼  还有庄家的
There's one for Tabes, and Chessy, and Martini, and the dealer.
塔波的是4  一个6  一个9...
And a four to Tabes, and a six, and a nine...
庄家是10
and a ten to the dealer.
一个9?
A nine?
塔波  你要不要?
What do you say, Tabes?
10分钱一张?
A dime a piece.
不要?
No? You stick.
-他不要牌  -他只要4
-He sticks.  -He sticks with a four.
契士要上路了
Chessy's going for the ride.
那是什么意思?
What does that mean?
他要一张牌  一张Q
He wants a hit. Yeah, and a big queen.
我想你爆了
I think you're busted.
是捉到了  不是爆了
Buggered, not busted.
-捉你  -捉到了
-Turn them over.  -Buggered.
你输了
And weep.
给我一张牌
Hit me.
我想你爆了
I think you're over.
-我知道你爆了  -没有啊
-I know you're over.  -Hovno.
-这张是3  -还没有爆
-That's a three.  -Hovno.
西佛特先生?
Mr. Sefelt?
一切顺利吗?
Did everything go well?
非常好
That's very nice.
你现在感觉好多了吧?
Now you feel better, don't you?
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
麦克墨菲走了
McMurphy is out.
麦克墨菲跑掉了
McMurphy has escaped.
他们带他经过走廊时
They were taking him through the tunnel.
他打倒两个看护  然后跑走了
He beat up two of the attendants and escaped.
麦克墨菲在楼上
McMurphy's upstairs.
不!
Oh, no, no, no!
吉姆  告诉你  麦克墨菲在楼上...
Jim, I'm telling you, McMurphy is upstairs...
他乖得像只绵羊
and he's as meek as a lamb.
真的?
Really?
你怎么知道的?
I mean, how do you know?
杰克・坦菲告诉我的
Jack Dunphy told me.
杰克・坦菲只会说废话!
Jack Dunphy's full of shit!
对!  没错!
Right! Right!
他们说你跑走了
They said you escaped.
我就知道你不会留下我
I knew you wouldn't leave without me.
我一直在等你
I was waiting for you.
现在我们可以走了
Now we can make it, Mac.
我现在感觉跟山一样壮
I feel big as a damn mountain.
不!
Oh, no!
我不会不带你走的  麦克
I'm not going without you, Mac.
我不会这样留下你的
I wouldn't leave you here this way.
你跟我走
You're coming with me.
我们走吧!
Let's go!